<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5.0 Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.0-data-cleaning-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.0-data-cleaning-qa/</guid>
      <description>In this section, Project Managers will find tools and resources to clean and upload field collected data to OpenStreetMap and manage data quality including:
 Step-by-step guides cleaning data in JOSM for upload to OpenStreetMap.
 Resources for data quality tools to use following upload to OpenStreetMap, including presentations.  Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance is a critical step in any mapping workflow. This process covers cleaning raw field data for errors and mistakes, uploading clean data to OpenStreetMap, and using various quality control tools to monitor data that has been uploaded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.1 Data Cleaning with JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.1-data-cleaning-with-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.1-data-cleaning-with-josm/</guid>
      <description>This section provides:
 An overview data cleaning tools in JOSM Step-by-step instructions for importing field data into JOSM Step-by-step instructions for cleaning data into JOSM  The following materials are designed to assist project managers and others leading trainings and workshops. However, this material is also suitable for individuals interested in learning how to clean and upload field data in JOSM.

Overview Data collected in the field should always be cleaned for errors and rectified with existing OSM data before upload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.4 Quality Assurance and Quality Control Tools</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.4-quality-assurance-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.4-quality-assurance-tools/</guid>
      <description>Overview Quality Assurance and Quality Control is the process by which mappers, and OpenStreetMap contributors in general, check data to ensure that all information uploaded to OSM meets high standards for usage and to prevent vandalism. As OpenStreetMap is a free and open platform that anyone can use and edit, it is critical to the sustainability of open data and OSM that everyone participates in the quality assurance and quality control process – from field data collection to data cleaning to long-term maintenance of existing OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>