<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digitization and Editing in OSM on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digitization and Editing in OSM on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/digitization-and-editing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3.1 Introduction to OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1_introduction_to_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1_introduction_to_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>Overview OpenStreetMap is a collaborative project to create a free editable world map and is at the core of HOT&amp;rsquo;s mapping activities. You are free to use it for any purpose as long as you credit OSM and its contributors.
The power of OpenStreetMap is that it empowers anyone, anywhere in the world to add information to a collective map and use the data for any purpose. You can think of OSM as the “Wikipedia of maps” – it is an online database and global community of over 5 million registered users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.2 Organized OSM Editing</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.2_organized_osm_editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.2_organized_osm_editing/</guid>
      <description>Before starting any mapping project, it is important to assess, and if necessary, update the OpenStreetMap basemap through remote mapping. This remote mapping process helps ensure that the buildings and roads used during a field mapping phase are up to date, improving the quality and effectiveness of field mapping efforts. For example, using remote mapping, your team can identify buildings or entire villages that might have been missed otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.3 Working with the HOT Tasking Manager</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3-working-with-the-hot-tasking-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3-working-with-the-hot-tasking-manager/</guid>
      <description>Overview The HOT Tasking Manager is a mapping tool designed and built for the Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team&amp;rsquo;s collaborative mapping process in OpenStreetMap. The purpose of the tool is to divide up a mapping project into smaller tasks that can be completed rapidly with many people working on the same overall area. It shows which areas need to be mapped and which areas need the mapping validated.
For information on Managing and Creating Projects on the HOT Tasking Manager, see [Managing Projects on Tasking Manager].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.4 Editing with iD and JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.4-editing-with-id-and-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.4-editing-with-id-and-josm/</guid>
      <description>Overview There are several ways to edit in OpenStreetMap. The two most commonly used tools and best programs for mapping projects are iD editor and JOSM. This section provides an overview of each tool as well as presentations to be used in trainings. For self-paced materials and guides, visit LearnOSM.
Comparison of Tools The iD editor is a user-friendly tool that allows you to directly make changes in OpenStreetMap. iD is good for:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.5 Validating with JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.5_validating_with_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.5_validating_with_josm/</guid>
      <description>Overview Validation is the process of checking the work of previous mappers for accuracy, consistency, completeness and anomaly. Validation is important to maintain the quality of OSM data. While light validation can be completed using iD Editor, HOT recommends that detailed validation be completed using JOSM.
Skills and Technology Needed
 Computer Internet connection OSM account [JOSM]  Resources
Training Materials
 Presentation [1]  Practice Validation The following activity covers the process of validating bad OSM data in JOSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.6 Resolving conflicts in JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.6-data-conflict-in-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.6-data-conflict-in-josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Participants can explain what is data conflict on OpenStreetMap Participants knowing about types of conflict in JOSM Participants can fix data conflicts using JOSM Participants know to avoid data conflict in JOSM  When you are uploading your changes in JSOM, some contributors might also do editing in your area. This might occur data conflict in your uploading process. Therefore, in this module, you will learn about data conflict in OpenStreetMap, types of conflict, and how to fix it using JOSM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>