<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/digitization-and-editing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3.1 Working with the HOT Tasking Manager</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1-working-with-the-hot-tasking-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1-working-with-the-hot-tasking-manager/</guid>
      <description>The HOT Tasking Manager is a mapping tool designed and built for the Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team&amp;rsquo;s collaborative mapping process in OpenStreetMap. The purpose of the tool is to divide up a mapping project into smaller tasks that can be completed rapidly with many people working on the same overall area. It shows which areas need to be mapped and which areas need the mapping validated.
Note: To become a project manager send an email to info@hotosm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.2 Working With Imagery</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.2-working-with-imagery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.2-working-with-imagery/</guid>
      <description>Assessing available imagery Satellite imagery There is only a limited number of companies/satellites that actually capture most of the available satellite imagery, with many more resellers providing access to and selling imagery. See Wikipedia for a good introduction. When assessing the imagery available for your project, try to look for:
 Freshness (the date of the imagery) Resolution Quality (color, contract, obliqueness/angle of imagery, lack of cloud cover)  Some useful tools to help in this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.3 Editing with iD and JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3-editing-with-id-and-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3-editing-with-id-and-josm/</guid>
      <description>There are several ways to edit in OpenStreetMap. The two most commonly used tools and best programs for mapping projects are iD editor and JOSM.
iD Editor
The iD editor is a user-friendly tool that allows you to directly make changes in OpenStreetMap. iD is good for:
 Simple edits Fast Internet access to load the imagery and save the edits. Following a consistent and simple tagging scheme. When you are restricted from installing a program on the computer you are using.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>