<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Teams in the Field using OSMTracker and QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/managing_teams_in_the_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/managing_teams_in_the_field/</guid>
      <description>Overview Central to effective and successful field data collection is a well thought out field data collection plan. This will ensure that field teams face the least number of challenges while out in the field, thus reducing the number of calls for field support coming to the supervisor.
When planning to deploy a team, it is important for the Supervisor to have a good picture of how many work days they have versus the man power available to do the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.4-creating-maps-in-print-composer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.4-creating-maps-in-print-composer/</guid>
      <description>Creating a New Print Composer
Open the ‘Project’ menu from the main toolbar, and select ‘New Print Composer’. In the pop-up window, create a title for your map. This can be a unique name to describe your map’s purpose such as “Political Map of Liberia” or simple such as “Map 1”.
A new window will be created with a blank page. This shows how your map will look printed out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/pages/getting_started/1.1_understanding_the_hot_tool_ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/getting_started/1.1_understanding_the_hot_tool_ecosystem/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/pages/getting_started/1.2_mapping_project_workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/getting_started/1.2_mapping_project_workflows/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.3 Hardware</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.3-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.3-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Hardware encompasses all physical assets related to technology, computers, and electronics needed for a project. When designing a mapping project, managers will need to assess what hardware, and specifications, are necessary to complete the work. While the anticipated project workflow influences the selection of hardware, it is important to note that the availability of technology and resources for procurement may place restrictions on hardware selection. In this way, hardware availability can also influence the workflow, making hardware selection an important part of the planning process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.5.1 Setting up phones and servers</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.5.1-setting-up-phones-and-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.5.1-setting-up-phones-and-servers/</guid>
      <description>Setting up phones for data collection Device set-up and testing instructions for OpenDataKit (ODK), OpenMapKit (OMK), and OSMTracker can be found here.
Open Data Kit (ODK) Download application For information on downloading and installing ODK, go to Data Collection Applications.
Tool set-up  Find the ODK Collect app icon on your mobile device and tap to open the app. After downloading the ODK app, an odk folder will be automatically created in on the internal memory of the device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.8 Trainings and Workshops</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.8-trainings-and-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.8-trainings-and-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Overview This section covers considerations and resources to use while planning trainings and workshops for mapping and OSM.
Training Requirements Attendee requirements
Requirements for attendees will vary depending on the scope of the trainings, the intended participants, and the available resources. No matter the scope of the training, it is important to communicate these requirements BEFORE the training so that participants can come prepared.
Some attendee requirements may include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.1 OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1_introduction_to_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1_introduction_to_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>OpenStreetMap is a collaborative project to create a free editable world map and is at the core of HOT&amp;rsquo;s mapping activities. You are free to use it for any purpose as long as you credit OSM and its contributors.
The power of OpenStreetMap is that it empowers anyone, anywhere in the world to add information to a collective map and use the data for any purpose. You can think of OSM as the “Wikipedia of maps” – it is an online database and global community of over 5 million registered users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.1.1 Opening OSM accounts</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1.1-opening_osm_accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1.1-opening_osm_accounts/</guid>
      <description>With OpenStreetMap (OSM) at the core of mapping activities, it is critical that all team members and participants have activated OSM accounts. This will be necessary before using many mapping tools such as HOT Tasking Manager, JOSM, and HOT Export Tool.
Skills and Technology Needed
 Computer Activated email account Internet connection  Creating an OSM Account
To get started, you will need to create an account on www.openstreetmap.org. Please use the “Sign Up” tab in the top right corner to begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.1.2 Getting started with OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1.2-getting-started-with-osm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1.2-getting-started-with-osm/</guid>
      <description>Objective:
 To be able to operate and navigate the OpenStreetMap website To be able to see object information in OpenStreetMap To be able to create share link in OpenStreetMap To be able to save images from OpenStreetMap To be able to create user account in OpenStreetMap To be able to understand the basic concept of attribute in OpenStreetMap To be able to understand history in OpenStreetMap  After you understand the basic of OpenStreetMap in the previous module, you can immediately start using OpenStreetMap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.2 Organized OSM Editing</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.2_organized_osm_editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.2_organized_osm_editing/</guid>
      <description>Before starting any mapping project, it is important to assess, and if necessary, update the OpenStreetMap basemap through remote mapping. This remote mapping process helps ensure that the buildings and roads used during a field mapping phase are up to date, improving the quality and effectiveness of field mapping efforts. For example, using remote mapping, your team can identify buildings or entire villages that might have been missed otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.3 Working with the HOT Tasking Manager</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3-working-with-the-hot-tasking-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3-working-with-the-hot-tasking-manager/</guid>
      <description>Overview The HOT Tasking Manager is a mapping tool designed and built for the Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team&amp;rsquo;s collaborative mapping process in OpenStreetMap. The purpose of the tool is to divide up a mapping project into smaller tasks that can be completed rapidly with many people working on the same overall area. It shows which areas need to be mapped and which areas need the mapping validated.
For information on Managing and Creating Projects on the HOT Tasking Manager, see [Managing Projects on Tasking Manager].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.3.2 Working With Imagery</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3.2-working-with-imagery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3.2-working-with-imagery/</guid>
      <description>Assessing available imagery Satellite imagery There is only a limited number of companies/satellites that actually capture most of the available satellite imagery, with many more resellers providing access to and selling imagery. See Wikipedia for a good introduction. When assessing the imagery available for your project, try to look for:
 Freshness (the date of the imagery) Resolution Quality (color, contract, obliqueness/angle of imagery, lack of cloud cover)  Some useful tools to help in this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.4 Editing with iD and JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.4-editing-with-id-and-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.4-editing-with-id-and-josm/</guid>
      <description>There are several ways to edit in OpenStreetMap. The two most commonly used tools and best programs for mapping projects are iD editor and JOSM.
iD Editor
The iD editor is a user-friendly tool that allows you to directly make changes in OpenStreetMap. iD is good for:
 Simple edits Fast Internet access to load the imagery and save the edits. Following a consistent and simple tagging scheme. When you are restricted from installing a program on the computer you are using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.5 Validating with JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.5_validating_with_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.5_validating_with_josm/</guid>
      <description>Overview Validation is the process of checking the work of previous mappers for accuracy, consistency, completeness and anomaly. Validation is important to maintain the quality of OSM data. While light validation can be completed using iD Editor, HOT recommends that detailed validation be completed using JOSM.
Skills and Technology Needed
 Computer Internet connection OSM account [JOSM]  Resources
Training Materials
 Presentation [1]  Practice Validation The following activity covers the process of validating bad OSM data in JOSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.6 Resolving conflicts in JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.6-data-conflict-in-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.6-data-conflict-in-josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Participants can explain what is data conflict on OpenStreetMap Participants knowing about types of conflict in JOSM Participants can fix data conflicts using JOSM Participants know to avoid data conflict in JOSM  When you are uploading your changes in JSOM, some contributors might also do editing in your area. This might occur data conflict in your uploading process. Therefore, in this module, you will learn about data conflict in OpenStreetMap, types of conflict, and how to fix it using JOSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.1 Designing The Data Model</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.1-designing-the-data-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.1-designing-the-data-model/</guid>
      <description>Overview When beginning a mapping project, a data model will need to be created in order to determine what features are mapped and the details collected for each of those features. A data model defines what features are surveyed or mapped and what attributes are collected for each feature. If a project will upload data to OpenStreetMap, the data model should be designed to match OSM tagging.
Example data models:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.2 Data collection applications</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2-data-collection-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2-data-collection-applications/</guid>
      <description>Overview Several mobile applications exist to assist with field data collection. Choosing an application to use depends on mobile device capability, varying set-up requirements, and survey needs. Options include OpenDataKit, OpenMapKit, KoboCollect, OSMTracker, and Maps.me
Which data collection application should I use?
   I want to collect&amp;hellip; ODK Kobo OMK Maps.me OSM Tracker Mapillary     Qualitative survey data ✔ ✔ ✔ × × ×   Quantitative survey data ✔ ✔ ✔ × × ×   GPS Points ✔ ✔ ✔ ✔ ✔ ×   Photos attached to GPS Points ✔ ✔ × × ✔ ×   GPX Tracks × × × × ✔ ✔   Streetview imagery × × × × × ✔   Data attached to OSM points of interest × × ✔ ✔ × ×   Data attached to OSM polygons (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.3 Navigation Applications</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.3-navigation-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.3-navigation-applications/</guid>
      <description>Overview Several mobile applications exist to assist with field navigation using OpenStreetMap as a baselayer and functioning offline for low-connection environments. Options include OSMAnd [1] and Maps.me [2].
While navigation tools are not required for data collection, they can be extremely useful for data collection teams in navigating to field locations, as well as for supervisors and project managers to understand where their teams have been.
Additional benefits of navigation applications include: * Collecting GPX tracks: GPX tracks can be used to record field movement as well as recording highway and road routes for later digitization and upload to OSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.4 Creating forms for ODK &amp; OMK</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.4-creating-forms-odk-omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.4-creating-forms-odk-omk/</guid>
      <description>Survey Form Design When using ODK and OMK survey applications, you will need to create the files that will serve as the survey forms.
Creating ODK forms
Forms can be created using spreadsheet software (such as Excel or LibreCalc) or using the ODK Form Builder. Documentation on how to design a form can be found here.
 Example ODK form Blank ODK form  Creating OMK forms Forms for OMK are slightly altered from ODK forms to incorporate the OSM tagging scheme and need to be built using spreadsheet software (such as Excel or LibreCalc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.5 Creating .mbtiles</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.5-creating-.mbtiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.5-creating-.mbtiles/</guid>
      <description>Overview MBTiles (.mbtiles) is the file format used for storing map tiles as a single file - the most common use case as baselayers for mobile mapping applications. There are multiple tools to create mbtiles, with selection based on baselayer type (aerial imagery), addition of vector layers, file size, zoom, etc.
  I need .mbtiles with...  HOT Export Tool  Tile Mill  TileHuria    Aerial Imagery Basemap  X  ✅  ✅    OSM Basemap  ✅  X  ✅    Vector layers (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.6 Creating .osm Layers for OMK</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.6-creating-osm-layers-for-omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.6-creating-osm-layers-for-omk/</guid>
      <description>Overview To conduct data collection using OpenMapKit (OMK), you will need to create an .osm layer. This .osm layer provides the buildings for selection in the OMK application.
Skills and Technology Needed
 Computer Internet Connection JOSM Installed Basic JOSM skills  Creating an .osm layer with JOSM In JOSM, click the top-menu File &amp;gt; New Layer to start. Then click the top-menu File &amp;gt; Download Data.
In the &amp;lsquo;Download&amp;rsquo; window, click the tab &amp;lsquo;Download from Overpass API&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.7 Data Collection Servers</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.7-data-collection-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.7-data-collection-servers/</guid>
      <description>Overview When beginning a mapping project, many organizations ask if they need to have a server. After collecting data, you’ll need to get the data from the devices. Sometimes, it works to simply collect and process data directly from the data collection devices. However, this does not scale well when you get more people collecting data, and also means your data is not backed up - if you lose the device, you can lose the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.8 Adding Survey Data into OSM Using JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.8-add-survey-data-using-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.8-add-survey-data-using-josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to install plugin Utilsplugin2 To be able to merge all survey data To be able to save .osm file using JOSM To be able to download OSM data To be able to add satellite imagery layer on JOSM To be able to add and edit OSM data using JOSM To be able to upload changes into OSM To be able to view changes of OSM data in OSM website  Adding or mapping new objects in OSM is one way to enrich OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.1 Using ODK Collect</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.1_using_odk_collect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.1_using_odk_collect/</guid>
      <description>Overview Open Data Kit Collect (ODK Collect) is a data collection application on Android. ODK Collect can replace form survey from paper to digital. Therefore, this application will help the mapping and data collection activities in the field which also allow to save the location and photo information at once.
This guide provides surveyors, mappers and field supervisors with the skills to:
 Complete the initial setup for ODK Collect Use ODK Collect for data collection surveys  Initial Setup for ODK Collect 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.2 OMK Field Data Cleaning Workflow</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.2-omk-field-data-cleaning-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.2-omk-field-data-cleaning-workflow/</guid>
      <description>After field data collection with OMK, clean the data before upload to OSM. Below is an example version of the OMK Field Data Cleaning Procedure. This is provided for guidance but should be modified as needed.
Skills and Technology Needed * JOSM
Step 1. Create folders Create the folder structure for the data cleaning process.
 Create primary working folder: [omk_field_data_cleaning] Create a container folder: [village_name]_[current-date]. For example: akweteyman_2019-01-31 Create a sub-folders within the container folder:  Add a folder for the raw data: /01_raw_[yourOSMname] Add a folder for the working data: /02_working_[yourOSMname] Add a folder for the final data: /03_final_[yourOSMname]   Step 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.2 Using the OpenMapKit Application</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.2_using_openmapkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.2_using_openmapkit/</guid>
      <description>Overview OpenMapKit (OMK) is an additional application that is used to support ODK Collect in determining the position of objects found during precise and precise field surveys. OpenMapKit can be run through ODK Collect, after you open and select one of the available forms. In determining the location of an object, OpenMapKit requires a map background in the form of a satellite imagery or OSM map. If you use the OSM as the map background, the thing to note is that the data must be available on the OSM server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.3 Data Cleaning with JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.3-data-cleaning-with-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.3-data-cleaning-with-josm/</guid>
      <description>There are tools built into JOSM, as well as additional plugins that can assist with data quality control during the upload process.
 Filters is a built-in tool that allows you to disable, hide, select, and highlight specific groups of objects based on flexible custom parameters. This tool will help you to spot and avoid common mistakes, and review data. The Validation Tool is another built-in tool that will review and search for common errors as well as provide warnings about potentially problematic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.3 Using OSMTracker</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.3_using_osm_tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.3_using_osm_tracker/</guid>
      <description>Overview OSMTracker is an android application that allows us to record our survey data. Similar to GPS, OSMTracker is able to record waypoint and also track. If you want to learn more about GPS for field survey, you can see the GPS Module. What makes OSMTracker different with common GPS device is its capability to take pictures when you collect the survey data. With these images taken, it will make your mapping more easier because you can track back what object you have been taken and take a look into your pictures for more detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.4 Quality Assurance and Quality Control</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.4-quality-assurance-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.4-quality-assurance-tools/</guid>
      <description>Quality Assurance and Quality Control is the process by which mappers, and OpenStreetMap contributors in general, check data to ensure that all information uploaded to OSM meets high standards for usage and to prevent vandalism. As OpenStreetMap is a free and open platform that anyone can use and edit, it is critical to the sustainability of open data and OSM that everyone participates in the quality assurance and quality control process – from field data collection to data cleaning to long-term maintenance of existing OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.1 HOT Export Tool</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/6.1-hot-export-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/6.1-hot-export-tool/</guid>
      <description>Overview HOT Export Tool allows users to download OSM data by specifying tags, area of interest, and file type. Learning resources and walkthroughs can be found at the HOT Export Tool Learn page.
Tools and Technology Needed:
 Computer Internet Connection OSM Account  Presentation: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1RyHYVPZU5d4xJ1cpWga4QRdfohpEs-t9ylJ_HTJ7wm8/edit#slide=id.g51e1e04424_0_238 Downloading OSM data with the HOT Export Tool Estimated time: [x min] To get started, open an internet browser and go to: https://export.hotosm.org/ To use the HOT Export Tool, you will need to log in using your OSM username and password, by clicking the red “Log In” button in the top right-hand corner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.2 Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX)</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/6.2-hdx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/6.2-hdx/</guid>
      <description>Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX) is a data platform for storing and sharing humanitarian data. The platform is managed by OCHA&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Humanitarian Data. Types of data available on HDX include: Data includes:
 Geospatial datasets CSVs &amp;amp; spreadsheets text &amp;amp; image files  Working with HDX In this activity, you will practice using Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX) for downloading OSM data for use in QGIS. HDX is an online-based tool, so you will need to be patient with internet connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.1 Introduction to QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Overview QGIS (or Quantum GIS) is a free and open source geographic information system (GIS) program. GIS programs allow users to display, manage, and analyze geospatial information on the computer, and create map products. Geospatial data that can be used in GIS includes aerial imagery, GPS data, and spatial datasets.
This section covers the basic skills necessary to using QGIS. These skills include:
 Installing QGIS Navigating QGIS Adding data Styling layers Installing Plugins  Installing and using QuickMapServices Installing and using QuickOSM   Following completion of this section, a new user should be prepared to navigate and work with data in QGIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.1.5 Creating an Atlas in QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.5-creating-an-atlas-in-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.5-creating-an-atlas-in-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Creating an atlas in QGIS allows users to create a series of maps for geographic regions with a set template. This atlas template allows for a large number of maps to be generated for areas of interest, such as districts, wards, and other administrative areas, with the same style and layout.
HOT Project Examples:
 Ramani Huria (Dar es Salaam, Tanzania) LEGIT (Liberia)  Training Activity Presentation:
Estimated time:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.4 OSM Analytics</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.4-osm-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.4-osm-analytics/</guid>
      <description>OSM Analytics allows users to understand more about how and when editing took place, or assess quality within OSM, use the OSM Analytics suite of tools. You can view how data has changed over time within OSM, understand quality within an area, or analyze what type of data is available.
More information about OSM Analytics can be found here and here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety, Security, and Logistics for Field Operations</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/field_operations-safety_security_and_logistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/field_operations-safety_security_and_logistics/</guid>
      <description>Overview [add]
Logistics There are many components to managing logistics for field operations. The topics listed below are just a few components that we recommend all organizations and communities consider prior to starting field mapping activities.
Workspace / Meeting space
 Do your operations require a workspace or meeting place? Does your operations require a central base with full-day access and wi-fi?  Equipment
Different scopes of work will require different types of equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow Example - Field Mapping Buildings and POI</title>
      <link>/pages/getting_started/1.2.1_example_fieldmappingbuildings_poi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/getting_started/1.2.1_example_fieldmappingbuildings_poi/</guid>
      <description>The following workflow showcases the tools and processes used in a long-term field mapping project to map buildings and points of interest using OpenMapKit with government and local partners.
Local Empowerment for Government Inclusion and Transparency (LEGIT) The Liberia Local Empowerment for Government Inclusion and Transparency (LEGIT) project supports the Ministry of Internal Affairs and Governance Commission as they lead, monitor and coordinate the implementation of the government’s decentralization agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>