<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.4-creating-maps-in-print-composer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.4-creating-maps-in-print-composer/</guid>
      <description>Creating a New Print Composer
Open the ‘Project’ menu from the main toolbar, and select ‘New Print Composer’. In the pop-up window, create a title for your map. This can be a unique name to describe your map’s purpose such as “Political Map of Liberia” or simple such as “Map 1”.
A new window will be created with a blank page. This shows how your map will look printed out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.1-mapping-project-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.1-mapping-project-workflow/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.1.1 LEGIT Project Workflow</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.1.1-legit-project-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.1.1-legit-project-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Local Empowerment for Government Inclusion and Transparency (LEGIT) The Liberia Local Empowerment for Government Inclusion and Transparency (LEGIT) project supports the Ministry of Internal Affairs and Governance Commission as they lead, monitor and coordinate the implementation of the government’s decentralization agenda.
HOT, in close coordination with the LEGIT project team, have contributed to several areas of the project, working with the Ministry of Internal Affairs (MIA)’s Department of Urban Affairs, city administrations in the cities of Gbarnga, Ganta and Zwedru, and selected CSOs and CBOs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.3 Hardware</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.3-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.3-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Mobile data collection: smartphones &amp;amp; tablets Smartphones versus tablets When choosing a type of device for mobile data collection, it is important to determine if a smartphone or tablet is more appropriate for mapping activities. Each device types have pros and cons, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand what is best for a particular project, mapper, and environment.
When planning to use OpenDataKit:
Most any Android smartphone will do, as long as it has a relativy modern Android version (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.4 Safety and Security for Field Operations</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.4-safety-and-security-for-field-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.4-safety-and-security-for-field-operations/</guid>
      <description>Each context is so different that it is difficult to make specific recommendations for safety. Communities and organizations conducting mapping activities should establish contingency plans to address the different types of security incidents that may occur. Team members should coordinate all responses to such incidents so as to safeguard the rights and well-being of local community members, and ensure that staff members and volunteers are not put at risk.
For operations, the key to effective safety and security management is the creation of a culture of security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.5.1 Setting up phones and servers</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.5.1-setting-up-phones-and-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.5.1-setting-up-phones-and-servers/</guid>
      <description>Setting up phones for data collection Device set-up and testing instructions for OpenDataKit (ODK), OpenMapKit (OMK), and OSMTracker can be found here.
Open Data Kit (ODK) Download application For information on downloading and installing ODK, go to Data Collection Applications.
Tool set-up  Find the ODK Collect app icon on your mobile device and tap to open the app. After downloading the ODK app, an odk folder will be automatically created in on the internal memory of the device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.8 Trainings and Workshops</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.8-trainings-and-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/1.8-trainings-and-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Overview This section covers considerations and resources to use while planning trainings and workshops for mapping and OSM.
Training Requirements Attendee requirements
Requirements for attendees will vary depending on the scope of the trainings, the intended participants, and the available resources. No matter the scope of the training, it is important to communicate these requirements BEFORE the training so that participants can come prepared.
Some attendee requirements may include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.1 OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>/pages/core-technology/2.1-openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/core-technology/2.1-openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>OpenStreetMap is a collaborative project to create a free editable world map and is at the core of HOT&amp;rsquo;s mapping activities. You are free to use it for any purpose as long as you credit OSM and its contributors.
The power of OpenStreetMap is that it empowers anyone, anywhere in the world to add information to a collective map and use the data for any purpose. You can think of OSM as the “Wikipedia of maps” – it is an online database and global community of over 5 million registered users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.1.1 Opening OSM accounts</title>
      <link>/pages/core-technology/2.1.1-opening-osm-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/core-technology/2.1.1-opening-osm-accounts/</guid>
      <description>With OpenStreetMap (OSM) at the core of mapping activities, it is critical that all team members and participants have activated OSM accounts. This will be necessary before using many mapping tools such as HOT Tasking Manager, JOSM, and HOT Export Tool.
Skills and Technology Needed
 Computer Activated email account Internet connection  Creating an OSM Account
To get started, you will need to create an account on www.openstreetmap.org. Please use the “Sign Up” tab in the top right corner to begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.1 Working with the HOT Tasking Manager</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1-working-with-the-hot-tasking-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.1-working-with-the-hot-tasking-manager/</guid>
      <description>The HOT Tasking Manager is a mapping tool designed and built for the Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team&amp;rsquo;s collaborative mapping process in OpenStreetMap. The purpose of the tool is to divide up a mapping project into smaller tasks that can be completed rapidly with many people working on the same overall area. It shows which areas need to be mapped and which areas need the mapping validated.
Note: To become a project manager send an email to info@hotosm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.2 Working With Imagery</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.2-working-with-imagery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.2-working-with-imagery/</guid>
      <description>Assessing available imagery Satellite imagery There is only a limited number of companies/satellites that actually capture most of the available satellite imagery, with many more resellers providing access to and selling imagery. See Wikipedia for a good introduction. When assessing the imagery available for your project, try to look for:
 Freshness (the date of the imagery) Resolution Quality (color, contract, obliqueness/angle of imagery, lack of cloud cover)  Some useful tools to help in this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.3 Editing with iD and JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3-editing-with-id-and-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/digitization-and-editing/3.3-editing-with-id-and-josm/</guid>
      <description>There are several ways to edit in OpenStreetMap. The two most commonly used tools and best programs for mapping projects are iD editor and JOSM.
iD Editor
The iD editor is a user-friendly tool that allows you to directly make changes in OpenStreetMap. iD is good for:
 Simple edits Fast Internet access to load the imagery and save the edits. Following a consistent and simple tagging scheme. When you are restricted from installing a program on the computer you are using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.1.2 Designing The Data Model</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.1.2-designing-the-data-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.1.2-designing-the-data-model/</guid>
      <description>Tagging Tags are used in OSM to categorize features, and to add information that is useful for:
 Understanding of the map Planning Routing Querying  OSM doesn’t work with layers or attribute tables, but tags. Each tag consists of a key, and a value. Each map feature should have 1 or more tags Such as:
 building=residential highway=primary amenity=school  Resources  Check the OpenStreetMap wiki. Start at the Map features page, search, and discover!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.2 Data collection applications</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2-data-collection-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2-data-collection-applications/</guid>
      <description>Overview Several mobile applications exist to assist with field data collection. Choosing an application to use depends on mobile device capability, varying set-up requirements, and survey needs. Options include OpenDataKit, OpenMapKit, KoboCollect, OSMTracker, and Maps.me
Which data collection application should I use?
   I want to collect&amp;hellip; ODK Kobo OMK Maps.me OSM Tracker Mapillary     Qualitative survey data ✔ ✔ ✔ × × ×   Quantitative survey data ✔ ✔ ✔ × × ×   GPS Points ✔ ✔ ✔ ✔ ✔ ×   Photos attached to GPS Points ✔ ✔ × × ✔ ×   GPX Tracks × × × × ✔ ✔   Streetview imagery × × × × × ✔   Data attached to OSM points of interest × × ✔ ✔ × ×   Data attached to OSM polygons (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.3 Navigation Applications</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.3-navigation-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.3-navigation-applications/</guid>
      <description>Several mobile applications exist to assist with field navigation using OpenStreetMap as a baselayer and functioning offline for low-connection environments. Options include OSMAnd and Maps.me
1. OSMAnd OSMAnd is a global mobile map viewing and navigation app for online and offline OSM Maps. It is used for recording tracks as well as mapping features. It provides easy way to record and submit information in the field.
Skills and Technology Needed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.4 Creating forms (ODK OMK)</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.4-creating-forms-odk-omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.4-creating-forms-odk-omk/</guid>
      <description>Form design Creating ODK forms
Forms can be created using spreadsheet software (such as Excel or LibreCalc) or using the ODK Form Builder. Documentation on how to design a form can be found here.
 Example ODK form Blank ODK form  Creating OMK forms Forms for OMK are slightly altered from ODK forms to incorporate the OSM tagging scheme and need to be built using spreadsheet software (such as Excel or LibreCalc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.5 Creating .mbtiles</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.5-creating-.mbtiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.5-creating-.mbtiles/</guid>
      <description>Overview MBTiles (.mbtiles) is the file format used for storing map tiles as a single file - the most common use case as baselayers for mobile mapping applications. There are multiple tools to create mbtiles, with selection based on baselayer type (aerial imagery), addition of vector layers, file size, zoom, etc.
  I need .mbtiles with...  HOT Export Tool  Tile Mill  TileHuria    Aerial Imagery Basemap  X  ✅  ✅    OSM Basemap  ✅  X  ✅    Vector layers (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.6 Creating .osm Layers for OMK</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.6-creating-osm-layers-for-omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.6-creating-osm-layers-for-omk/</guid>
      <description>Overview To conduct data collection using OpenMapKit (OMK), you will need to create an .osm layer. This .osm layer provides the buildings for selection in the OMK application.
Skills and Technology Needed
 Computer Internet Connection JOSM Installed Basic JOSM skills  Creating an .osm layer with JOSM In JOSM, click the top-menu File &amp;gt; New Layer to start. Then click the top-menu File &amp;gt; Download Data.
In the &amp;lsquo;Download&amp;rsquo; window, click the tab &amp;lsquo;Download from Overpass API&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.7 Data Collection Servers</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.7-data-collection-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.7-data-collection-servers/</guid>
      <description>Overview When beginning a mapping project, many organizations ask if they need to have a server. After collecting data, you’ll need to get the data from the devices. Sometimes, it works to simply collect and process data directly from the data collection devices. However, this does not scale well when you get more people collecting data, and also means your data is not backed up - if you lose the device, you can lose the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.1.1 Server Data</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.1.1-server-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.1.1-server-data/</guid>
      <description>Server data in this case refers to data sent to a server from the field. This data then has to be downloaded from the server, in order to prepare it for cleaning and validation. We will take for example data collected during the NMP Building Validation Project in Botswana. Servers used can be:
 A local Portable OpenStreetMap Server - POSM (for both ODK and OMK data) An online OpenMapKit Server (for both ODK and OMK data) KoboToolbox (for only ODK data)  Preparing OMK Data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.1.2 Serverless Data</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.1.2-serverless-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.1.2-serverless-data/</guid>
      <description>Serverless data in this case refers to data collected without the use of a server to receive field data. In order to clean and validate this data, it is copied from data collection devices (phones or tablets) directly. We will take for example data collected during the Local Empowerment for Government Inclusion and Transparency Project in Liberia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.2 OMK Field Data Cleaning Workflow</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.2-omk-field-data-cleaning-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.2-omk-field-data-cleaning-workflow/</guid>
      <description>After field data collection with OMK, clean the data before upload to OSM. Below is an example version of the OMK Field Data Cleaning Procedure. This is provided for guidance but should be modified as needed.
Skills and Technology Needed * JOSM
Step 1. Create folders Create the folder structure for the data cleaning process.
 Create primary working folder: [omk_field_data_cleaning] Create a container folder: [village_name]_[current-date]. For example: akweteyman_2019-01-31 Create a sub-folders within the container folder:  Add a folder for the raw data: /01_raw_[yourOSMname] Add a folder for the working data: /02_working_[yourOSMname] Add a folder for the final data: /03_final_[yourOSMname]   Step 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.3 Data Cleaning with JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.3-data-cleaning-with-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.3-data-cleaning-with-josm/</guid>
      <description>There are tools built into JOSM, as well as additional plugins that can assist with data quality control during the upload process.
 Filters is a built-in tool that allows you to disable, hide, select, and highlight specific groups of objects based on flexible custom parameters. This tool will help you to spot and avoid common mistakes, and review data. The Validation Tool is another built-in tool that will review and search for common errors as well as provide warnings about potentially problematic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.4 Quality Assurance and Quality Control</title>
      <link>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.4-quality-assurance-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.4-quality-assurance-tools/</guid>
      <description>Quality Assurance and Quality Control is the process by which mappers, and OpenStreetMap contributors in general, check data to ensure that all information uploaded to OSM meets high standards for usage and to prevent vandalism. As OpenStreetMap is a free and open platform that anyone can use and edit, it is critical to the sustainability of open data and OSM that everyone participates in the quality assurance and quality control process – from field data collection to data cleaning to long-term maintenance of existing OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.1 HOT Export Tool</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/6.1-hot-export-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/6.1-hot-export-tool/</guid>
      <description>Overview HOT Export Tool allows users to download OSM data by specifying tags, area of interest, and file type. Learning resources and walkthroughs can be found at the HOT Export Tool Learn page.
Tools and Technology Needed:
 Computer Internet Connection OSM Account  Presentation: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1RyHYVPZU5d4xJ1cpWga4QRdfohpEs-t9ylJ_HTJ7wm8/edit#slide=id.g51e1e04424_0_238 Downloading OSM data with the HOT Export Tool Estimated time: [x min] To get started, open an internet browser and go to: https://export.hotosm.org/ To use the HOT Export Tool, you will need to log in using your OSM username and password, by clicking the red “Log In” button in the top right-hand corner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.2 Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX)</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/6.2-hdx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/6.2-hdx/</guid>
      <description>Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX) is a data platform for storing and sharing humanitarian data. The platform is managed by OCHA&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Humanitarian Data. Types of data available on HDX include: Data includes:
 Geospatial datasets CSVs &amp;amp; spreadsheets text &amp;amp; image files  Working with HDX In this activity, you will practice using Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX) for downloading OSM data for use in QGIS. HDX is an online-based tool, so you will need to be patient with internet connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.1 Introduction to QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Overview QGIS (or Quantum GIS) is a free and open source geographic information system (GIS) program. GIS programs allow users to display, manage, and analyze geospatial information on the computer, and create map products. Geospatial data that can be used in GIS includes aerial imagery, GPS data, and spatial datasets.
This section covers the basic skills necessary to using QGIS. These skills include:
 Installing QGIS Navigating QGIS Adding data Styling layers Installing Plugins  Installing and using QuickMapServices Installing and using QuickOSM   Following completion of this section, a new user should be prepared to navigate and work with data in QGIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.1.5 Creating an Atlas in QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.5-creating-an-atlas-in-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.5-creating-an-atlas-in-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Creating an atlas in QGIS allows users to create a series of maps for geographic regions with a set template. This atlas template allows for a large number of maps to be generated for areas of interest, such as districts, wards, and other administrative areas, with the same style and layout.
HOT Project Examples:
 Ramani Huria (Dar es Salaam, Tanzania) LEGIT (Liberia)  Training Activity Presentation:
Estimated time:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.4 OSM Analytics</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.4-osm-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.4-osm-analytics/</guid>
      <description>OSM Analytics allows users to understand more about how and when editing took place, or assess quality within OSM, use the OSM Analytics suite of tools. You can view how data has changed over time within OSM, understand quality within an area, or analyze what type of data is available.
More information about OSM Analytics can be found here and here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>