<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>6.0 Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance</title>
      <link>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.0-data-cleaning-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.0-data-cleaning-qa/</guid>
      <description>Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance is a critical step in any mapping workflow. This process covers cleaning raw field data for errors and mistakes, uploading clean data to OpenStreetMap, and using various quality control tools to monitor data that has been uploaded. Regardless of how (and if) you are collecting field data, any project that results edits in OpenStreetMap should have a quality assurance and control plan.
 6.1 Management of Collected Data covers the best practices and recommend workflows for managing data that is collected in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.3 Data Cleaning with JOSM</title>
      <link>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.3-data-cleaning-with-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.3-data-cleaning-with-josm/</guid>
      <description>Overview Data collected in the field should always be cleaned for errors and rectified with existing OSM data before upload. There are a lot of OSM data editors available, but in this module the OSM data editor used is JOSM. JOSM has a lot of useful tools and plugins, making OSM mapping a lot easier but most importantly, it is the easiest tool and best tool for maintaining quality OSM data while importing batches of field data into OSM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>