<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>6.0 Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance</title>
      <link>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.0-data-cleaning-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.0-data-cleaning-qa/</guid>
      <description>Data Cleaning, Upload, and Quality Assurance is a critical step in any mapping workflow. This process covers cleaning raw field data for errors and mistakes, uploading clean data to OpenStreetMap, and using various quality control tools to monitor data that has been uploaded. Regardless of how (and if) you are collecting field data, any project that results edits in OpenStreetMap should have a quality assurance and control plan.
 6.1 Management of Collected Data covers the best practices and recommend workflows for managing data that is collected in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.2 OMK Field Data Cleaning Workflow</title>
      <link>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.2-omk-field-data-cleaning-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.2-omk-field-data-cleaning-workflow/</guid>
      <description>After field data collection with OMK, clean the data before upload to OSM. Below is an example version of the OMK Field Data Cleaning Procedure. This is provided for guidance but should be modified as needed.
Skills and Technology Needed * JOSM
Step 1. Create folders Create the folder structure for the data cleaning process.
 Create primary working folder: [omk_field_data_cleaning] Create a container folder: [village_name]_[current-date]. For example: akweteyman_2019-01-31 Create a sub-folders within the container folder:  Add a folder for the raw data: /01_raw_[yourOSMname] Add a folder for the working data: /02_working_[yourOSMname] Add a folder for the final data: /03_final_[yourOSMname]   Step 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.3 Data Cleaning with JOSM</title>
      <link>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.3-data-cleaning-with-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/6.3-data-cleaning-with-josm/</guid>
      <description>Overview Data collected in the field should always be cleaned for errors and rectified with existing OSM data before upload. There are a lot of OSM data editors available, but in this module the OSM data editor used is JOSM. JOSM has a lot of useful tools and plugins, making OSM mapping a lot easier but most importantly, it is the easiest tool and best tool for maintaining quality OSM data while importing batches of field data into OSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.4 Quality Assurance and Quality Control Tools</title>
      <link>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.4-quality-assurance-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/pages/data-cleaning-upload-and-quality-assurance/5.4-quality-assurance-tools/</guid>
      <description>Overview Quality Assurance and Quality Control is the process by which mappers, and OpenStreetMap contributors in general, check data to ensure that all information uploaded to OSM meets high standards for usage and to prevent vandalism. As OpenStreetMap is a free and open platform that anyone can use and edit, it is critical to the sustainability of open data and OSM that everyone participates in the quality assurance and quality control process – from field data collection to data cleaning to long-term maintenance of existing OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>