<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4.1 Designing The Data Model</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.1-designing-the-data-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.1-designing-the-data-model/</guid>
      <description>Overview When beginning a mapping project, a data model will need to be created in order to determine what features are mapped and the details collected for each of those features. A data model defines what features are surveyed or mapped and what attributes are collected for each feature. If a project will upload data to OpenStreetMap, the data model should be designed to match OSM tagging.
Example data models:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.2 Data collection applications</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2-data-collection-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2-data-collection-applications/</guid>
      <description>Overview Several mobile applications exist to assist with field data collection. Choosing an application to use depends on mobile device capability, varying set-up requirements, and survey needs. Options include OpenDataKit, OpenMapKit, KoboCollect, OSMTracker, and Maps.me
Which data collection application should I use?
   I want to collect&amp;hellip; ODK Kobo OMK Maps.me OSM Tracker Mapillary     Qualitative survey data ✔ ✔ ✔ × × ×   Quantitative survey data ✔ ✔ ✔ × × ×   GPS Points ✔ ✔ ✔ ✔ ✔ ×   Photos attached to GPS Points ✔ ✔ × × ✔ ×   GPX Tracks × × × × ✔ ✔   Streetview imagery × × × × × ✔   Data attached to OSM points of interest × × ✔ ✔ × ×   Data attached to OSM polygons (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.2.2 Setting up OpenMapKit</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2.2_setting_up_omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2.2_setting_up_omk/</guid>
      <description>Overview OpenMapKit (OMK) is an extension that launches directly from within OpenDataKit (ODK) Collect when the OpenStreetMap question type is enabled in a standard survey. It is what allows you to browse OSM features, and to create and edit OSM tags.
Not sure if OpenMapKit is right for your project? Review Data Collection Applications.
Set-up Process
 [Create OMK forms] [Create .mbtiles] [Create .osm layer] Create constraint file [Download and set up ODK and OMK applications] [Add all above files to mobile data collection devices]  Creating OMK Forms When using OMK survey applications, you will need to create the files that will serve as the survey forms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.3 Navigation Applications</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.3-navigation-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.3-navigation-applications/</guid>
      <description>Overview Several mobile applications exist to assist with field navigation using OpenStreetMap as a baselayer and functioning offline for low-connection environments. Options include OSMAnd [1] and Maps.me [2].
While navigation tools are not required for data collection, they can be extremely useful for data collection teams in navigating to field locations, as well as for supervisors and project managers to understand where their teams have been.
Additional benefits of navigation applications include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.4 Creating forms for ODK &amp; OMK</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.4-creating-forms-odk-omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.4-creating-forms-odk-omk/</guid>
      <description>Survey Form Design When using ODK and OMK survey applications, you will need to create the files that will serve as the survey forms.
Creating ODK forms
Forms can be created using spreadsheet software (such as Excel or LibreCalc) or using the ODK Form Builder. Documentation on how to design a form can be found here.
 Example ODK form Blank ODK form  Creating OMK forms Forms for OMK are slightly altered from ODK forms to incorporate the OSM tagging scheme and need to be built using spreadsheet software (such as Excel or LibreCalc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.5 Creating .mbtiles</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.5-creating-.mbtiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.5-creating-.mbtiles/</guid>
      <description>Overview MBTiles (.mbtiles) is the file format used for storing map tiles as a single file - the most common use case as baselayers for mobile mapping applications. There are multiple tools to create mbtiles, with selection based on baselayer type (aerial imagery), addition of vector layers, file size, zoom, etc. Many factors can influence the type of basemap that you need for your field data collection.
 If you are mapping buildings in areas that are rural and/or there are few landmarks in OSM, use an aerial imagery basemap mbtile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.6 Creating .osm Layers for OMK</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.6-creating-osm-layers-for-omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.6-creating-osm-layers-for-omk/</guid>
      <description>Overview To conduct data collection using OpenMapKit (OMK), you will need to create an .osm layer. This .osm layer provides the buildings for selection in the OMK application.
Skills and Technology Needed
 Computer Internet Connection JOSM Installed Basic JOSM skills  Creating an .osm layer with JOSM In JOSM, click the top-menu File &amp;gt; New Layer to start. Then click the top-menu File &amp;gt; Download Data.
In the &amp;lsquo;Download&amp;rsquo; window, click the tab &amp;lsquo;Download from Overpass API&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.7 Data Collection Servers</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.7-data-collection-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.7-data-collection-servers/</guid>
      <description>Overview When beginning a mapping project, many organizations ask if they need to have a server. After collecting data, you’ll need to get the data from the devices. Sometimes, it works to simply collect and process data directly from the data collection devices. However, this does not scale well when you get more people collecting data, and also means your data is not backed up - if you lose the device, you can lose the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.8 Adding Survey Data into OSM Using JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.8-add-survey-data-using-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.8-add-survey-data-using-josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to install plugin Utilsplugin2 To be able to merge all survey data To be able to save .osm file using JOSM To be able to download OSM data To be able to add satellite imagery layer on JOSM To be able to add and edit OSM data using JOSM To be able to upload changes into OSM To be able to view changes of OSM data in OSM website  Adding or mapping new objects in OSM is one way to enrich OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>