<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Field Mapping Technical Set-up on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Field Mapping Technical Set-up on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4.0 Field Mapping - Technical Set-up</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.0_technical_set-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.0_technical_set-up/</guid>
      <description>Any field project will require some degree of Field Mapping Technical Set-Up regardless of the complexity of the data collection workflow. This section is designed to guide project managers and community members through the decision making process to determine what tools and steps are necessary for their specific project. Many technical guides exist on setting up and using specific tools such as OpenDataKit and POSM. To support project managers effectively, step-by-step guides are provided for some tools and processes where external documentation is lacking or HOT has previously created tailored materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.1 Designing The Data Model</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.1-designing-the-data-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.1-designing-the-data-model/</guid>
      <description>Overview When beginning a mapping project, a data model will need to be created in order to determine what features are mapped and the details collected for each of those features. A data model defines what features are surveyed or mapped and what attributes are collected for each feature. If a project will upload data to OpenStreetMap, the data model should be designed to match OSM tagging.
Example data models:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.2 Data collection applications</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2-data-collection-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2-data-collection-applications/</guid>
      <description>Overview Several mobile applications exist to assist with field data collection. Choosing an application to use depends on mobile device capability, varying set-up requirements, and survey needs. Options include OpenDataKit, OpenMapKit, KoboCollect, OSMTracker, and Maps.me
Which data collection application should I use?
   I want to collect&amp;hellip; ODK Kobo OMK Maps.me OSM Tracker Mapillary     Qualitative survey data ✔ ✔ ✔ × × ×   Quantitative survey data ✔ ✔ ✔ × × ×   GPS Points ✔ ✔ ✔ ✔ ✔ ×   Photos attached to GPS Points ✔ ✔ × × ✔ ×   GPX Tracks × × × × ✔ ✔   Streetview imagery × × × × × ✔   Data attached to OSM points of interest × × ✔ ✔ × ×   Data attached to OSM polygons (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.2.2 Setting up OpenMapKit</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2.2_setting_up_omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.2.2_setting_up_omk/</guid>
      <description>Overview OpenMapKit (OMK) is an extension that launches directly from within OpenDataKit (ODK) Collect when the OpenStreetMap question type is enabled in a standard survey. It is what allows you to browse OSM features, and to create and edit OSM tags.
Not sure if OpenMapKit is right for your project? Review Data Collection Applications.
Set-up Process
 [Create OMK forms] [Create .mbtiles] [Create .osm layer] Create constraint file [Download and set up ODK and OMK applications] [Add all above files to mobile data collection devices]  Creating OMK Forms When using OMK survey applications, you will need to create the files that will serve as the survey forms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.3 Navigation Applications</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.3-navigation-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.3-navigation-applications/</guid>
      <description>Overview Several mobile applications exist to assist with field navigation using OpenStreetMap as a baselayer and functioning offline for low-connection environments. Options include OSMAnd [1] and Maps.me [2].
While navigation tools are not required for data collection, they can be extremely useful for data collection teams in navigating to field locations, as well as for supervisors and project managers to understand where their teams have been.
Additional benefits of navigation applications include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.7 Data Collection Servers</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.7-data-collection-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.7-data-collection-servers/</guid>
      <description>Overview When beginning a mapping project, many organizations ask if they need to have a server. After collecting data, you’ll need to get the data from the devices. Sometimes, it works to simply collect and process data directly from the data collection devices. However, this does not scale well when you get more people collecting data, and also means your data is not backed up - if you lose the device, you can lose the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.8 Adding Survey Data into OSM Using JOSM</title>
      <link>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.8-add-survey-data-using-josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-collection-and-field-mapping/4.8-add-survey-data-using-josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to install plugin Utilsplugin2 To be able to merge all survey data To be able to save .osm file using JOSM To be able to download OSM data To be able to add satellite imagery layer on JOSM To be able to add and edit OSM data using JOSM To be able to upload changes into OSM To be able to view changes of OSM data in OSM website  Adding or mapping new objects in OSM is one way to enrich OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>