<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Export Tools on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/data-export/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Export Tools on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/data-export/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>6.0 Introduction to Data Export Tools</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/6.0-data-export-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/6.0-data-export-tools/</guid>
      <description>In this section, Project Managers will find resources on how to export OpenStreetMap data, including:
 An overview of data export tools, including presentation slides
 Step-by-step guides for exporting data with the HOT Export Tool and HDX  Data Export Tools allow users to download OSM data for use and analysis programs such as QGIS. The following are Data Export Tools commonly used in the HOT workflow. For more information on how to use these tools, follow the step-by-step guides in each of the following sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.1 HOT Export Tool</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/6.1-hot-export-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/6.1-hot-export-tool/</guid>
      <description>This section provides:
 An overview of the HOT Export Tool Step-by-step instructions on downloading data (such as shapefiles) from OpenStreetMap using Export Tool  
Overview HOT Export Tool allows users to download OSM data by specifying tags, area of interest, and file type. Learning resources and walkthroughs can be found at the HOT Export Tool Learn page.

Training Materials for HOT Export Tool This section features a selection of resources targeted at project managers, trainers, or even self-learners on the topic(s) outlined above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.2 Humanitarian Data Exchange</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/6.2-hdx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/6.2-hdx/</guid>
      <description>This section provides:
 An overview of the Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX) Step-by-step instructions on downloading data (such as shapefiles) from OpenStreetMap using HDX  
Overview Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX) is a data platform for storing and sharing humanitarian data. The platform is managed by OCHA&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Humanitarian Data. Types of data available on HDX include: Data includes:
 Geospatial datasets CSVs &amp;amp; spreadsheets text &amp;amp; image files  Training Materials for HOT Export Tool This section features a selection of resources targeted at project managers, trainers, or even self-learners on the topic(s) outlined above.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>