<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Export Tools on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/data-export/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Export Tools on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/data-export/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7.0 Data Export Tools</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/7.0-data-export-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/7.0-data-export-tools/</guid>
      <description>Data Export Tools allow users to download OSM data for use and analysis programs such as QGIS. The following are Data Export Tools commonly used in the HOT workflow. For more information on how to use these tools, follow the step-by-step guides in each of the following sections.
 7.1 HOT Export Tool covers the HOT Export Tool which allows users to download OSM data by specifying tags, area of interest, and file type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.1 HOT Export Tool</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/6.1-hot-export-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/6.1-hot-export-tool/</guid>
      <description>Overview HOT Export Tool allows users to download OSM data by specifying tags, area of interest, and file type. Learning resources and walkthroughs can be found at the HOT Export Tool Learn page.
Tools and Technology Needed:
 Computer Internet Connection OSM Account  HOT Training Materials The following presentation(s) can be used to lead a training or workshop.
 Data Export Tools   The following section is designed to serve as self-paced material that can be used both during trainings, and by self-guided learners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.2 Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX)</title>
      <link>/pages/data-export/6.2-hdx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-export/6.2-hdx/</guid>
      <description>Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX) is a data platform for storing and sharing humanitarian data. The platform is managed by OCHA&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Humanitarian Data. Types of data available on HDX include: Data includes:
 Geospatial datasets CSVs &amp;amp; spreadsheets text &amp;amp; image files  Working with HDX In this activity, you will practice using Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX) for downloading OSM data for use in QGIS. HDX is an online-based tool, so you will need to be patient with internet connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>