<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Designing and Coordinating a Mapping Project on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Designing and Coordinating a Mapping Project on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/running-a-mapping-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2.2 Safety, Security, and Logistics for Field Operations</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/2.2_field_operations-safety_security_and_logistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/2.2_field_operations-safety_security_and_logistics/</guid>
      <description>Overview For projects requiring field work, you will need to take extra steps to ensure that logistics and security are effectively handled. The following are topics that project managers should consider and have plans for before entering the field. Work with donors, local partners, and stakeholders to fill information gaps and meet these needs.
Logistics There are many components to managing logistics for field operations. The topics listed below are just a few components that we recommend all organizations and communities consider prior to starting field mapping activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.3 Selecting Hardware</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/2.3-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/2.3-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Hardware encompasses all physical assets related to technology, computers, and electronics needed for a project. When designing a mapping project, managers will need to assess what hardware, and specifications, are necessary to complete the work. While the anticipated project workflow influences the selection of hardware, it is important to note that the availability of technology and resources for procurement may place restrictions on hardware selection. In this way, hardware availability can also influence the workflow, making hardware selection an important part of the planning process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.4 Trainings and Workshops</title>
      <link>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/2.4-trainings-and-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/running-a-mapping-project/2.4-trainings-and-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Overview This section covers considerations and resources to use while planning trainings and workshops for mapping and OSM.
Training Requirements Attendee requirements
Requirements for attendees will vary depending on the scope of the trainings, the intended participants, and the available resources. No matter the scope of the training, it is important to communicate these requirements BEFORE the training so that participants can come prepared.
Some attendee requirements may include:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>