<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Use and Analysis on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Use and Analysis on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/data-use-and-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7.0 Data Use and Analysis</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.0_data-use-and-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.0_data-use-and-analysis/</guid>
      <description>In this section, Project Managers will find tools and resources on how to use OSM data to create map products for decision-making including:
 A step-by-step guide for getting started with QGIS, including presentation slides A step-by-step guide for creating maps and atlases in QGIS Detailed guides and resources for using data in web and interactive maps  There are a handful of free Data Use and Analysis tools available to use your field generated data, extract and utilize OSM data, or combine datasets to create maps, atlases, and other visuals for decision making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8.1 Introduction to QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/8.1-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/8.1-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Overview QGIS (or Quantum GIS) is a free and open source geographic information system (GIS) program. GIS programs allow users to display, manage, and analyze geospatial information on the computer, and create map products. Geospatial data that can be used in GIS includes aerial imagery, GPS data, and spatial datasets.
This section covers the basic skills necessary to using QGIS. These skills include:
 Installing QGIS Navigating QGIS Adding data Styling layers Installing Plugins  Installing and using QuickMapServices Installing and using QuickOSM   Following completion of this section, a new user should be prepared to navigate and work with data in QGIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8.2 Creating Maps and Atlases in QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/8.2-creating-an-atlas-in-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/8.2-creating-an-atlas-in-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Creating an atlas in QGIS allows users to create a series of maps for geographic regions with a set template. This atlas template allows for a large number of maps to be generated for areas of interest, such as districts, wards, and other administrative areas, with the same style and layout.
HOT Project Examples:
 Ramani Huria (Dar es Salaam, Tanzania) LEGIT (Liberia)  Training Activity Presentation:
Estimated time:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8.3 Web &amp; Interactive Maps</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/8.3_web_and_interactive_maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/8.3_web_and_interactive_maps/</guid>
      <description>Overview Interactive maps are viewed as the modern equivalent of visual communication with maps. This involves the creation and study of the visual representation of data(maps). To communicate information clearly and efficiently, data visualization uses statistical graphics, plots, information graphics and other tools. The use of interactive maps gives users an opportunity to change the display of the map to one&amp;rsquo;s preferences freely.
This section covers two tools for creating interactive maps using OSM data: uMap and Overpass Turbo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>