<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Use and Analysis on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Use and Analysis on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/data-use-and-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.4-creating-maps-in-print-composer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.4-creating-maps-in-print-composer/</guid>
      <description>Creating a New Print Composer
Open the ‘Project’ menu from the main toolbar, and select ‘New Print Composer’. In the pop-up window, create a title for your map. This can be a unique name to describe your map’s purpose such as “Political Map of Liberia” or simple such as “Map 1”.
A new window will be created with a blank page. This shows how your map will look printed out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.1 Introduction to QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Overview QGIS (or Quantum GIS) is a free and open source geographic information system (GIS) program. GIS programs allow users to display, manage, and analyze geospatial information on the computer, and create map products. Geospatial data that can be used in GIS includes aerial imagery, GPS data, and spatial datasets.
This section covers the basic skills necessary to using QGIS. These skills include:
 Installing QGIS Navigating QGIS Adding data Styling layers Installing Plugins  Installing and using QuickMapServices Installing and using QuickOSM   Following completion of this section, a new user should be prepared to navigate and work with data in QGIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.1.5 Creating an Atlas in QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.5-creating-an-atlas-in-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.1.5-creating-an-atlas-in-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Creating an atlas in QGIS allows users to create a series of maps for geographic regions with a set template. This atlas template allows for a large number of maps to be generated for areas of interest, such as districts, wards, and other administrative areas, with the same style and layout.
HOT Project Examples:
 Ramani Huria (Dar es Salaam, Tanzania) LEGIT (Liberia)  Training Activity Presentation:
Estimated time:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.4 OSM Analytics</title>
      <link>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.4-osm-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/data-use-and-analysis/7.4-osm-analytics/</guid>
      <description>OSM Analytics allows users to understand more about how and when editing took place, or assess quality within OSM, use the OSM Analytics suite of tools. You can view how data has changed over time within OSM, understand quality within an area, or analyze what type of data is available.
More information about OSM Analytics can be found here and here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>