<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mapping Project Workflows on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/getting_started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mapping Project Workflows on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/getting_started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>8.0 Introduction to Mapping Workflows</title>
      <link>/pages/getting_started/8.0_mapping_workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/getting_started/8.0_mapping_workflows/</guid>
      <description>In this section, Project Managers will find example workflows from HOT projects on how the processes, tools, and workflows contained in previous sections of this Toolbox have been applied to real field projects. Project Managers can use these example workflows to identify a project similar in scope or goal to their own and identify which tools and processes may be needed for their own project. Each workflow example contains:
 An overview of the project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.1 Mapping Buildings and POI with OMK Workflow</title>
      <link>/pages/getting_started/1.2.1_example_fieldmappingbuildings_poi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/getting_started/1.2.1_example_fieldmappingbuildings_poi/</guid>
      <description>The following workflow showcases the tools and processes used in a long-term field mapping project to map buildings and points of interest using OpenMapKit with government and local partners.
Project Overview Open Cities Africa - Accra
The Open Cities Africa Accra project sought to make Alogboshie and its environs resilient to natural disasters, especially flooding. The project involved the remote mapping of Alogboshie, Akweteyman and Alajo. These are areas of focus in a larger resilience project, Greater Accra Resilience and Integrated Development (GARID), and are all located along the Odaw River which is prone to floods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.1 Mapping POI with ODK &#43; KoboToolbox Server</title>
      <link>/pages/getting_started/8.2_mappingpoi_withodk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/getting_started/8.2_mappingpoi_withodk/</guid>
      <description>The following workflow showcases the tools and processes used in a simple field mapping project used by a local NGO to integrate into existing programs using OpenDataKit and KoboToolBox Server.
Project Overview Bridging Gaps in Development and Emergency for the Refugee Crisis in East Africa
East Africa (and Uganda specifically) continues to be the center of one of the world’s largest and fastest growing refugee crises. Uganda’s progressive open-door policy alone has led to an influx of approximately 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>