<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Field Mapping Management on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Field Mapping Management on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/field-mapping-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ODK Collect Application</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/using_odk_collect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/using_odk_collect/</guid>
      <description>Objective:
 Able to explain ODK Collect as one of the tools to collect infrastructure data Able to set the initial setup for ODK Collect Able to apply how to use ODK Collect for data collection survey  I. What is ODK Collect? Open Data Kit Collect (ODK Collect) is a data collection application on Android. ODK Collect can replace form survey from paper to digital. Therefore, this application will help the mapping and data collection activities in the field which also allow to save the location and photo information at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the OpenMapKit Application</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/using_openmapkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/using_openmapkit/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Able to explain OpenMapkit as one of the tools for collecting infrastructure data Able to operate the initial setup for OpenMapKit Able to operate how to enter offline basemap for OpenMapKit Able to operate OpenMapKit  Previously you already learn the ODK (OpenDataKit) Collect, an android-based application to replace paper form for surveys. ODK Collect has extension called OpenMapKit (OMK). This extension is used to add information on the position or location of the object surveyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Teams in the Field using OSMTracker and QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/managing_teams_in_the_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/managing_teams_in_the_field/</guid>
      <description>Overview Central to effective and successful field data collection is a well thought out field data collection plan. This will ensure that field teams face the least number of challenges while out in the field, thus reducing the number of calls for field support coming to the supervisor.
When planning to deploy a team, it is important for the Supervisor to have a good picture of how many work days they have versus the man power available to do the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OSMTrackers</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/using_osm_tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/using_osm_tracker/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Explain OSMTracker as one of survey tools for recording tracks and photos
 How to set up the OSMTracker for the first time
 Learn how to use OSMTracker
  I. What is OSMTracker? OSMTracker is an android application that allows us to record our survey data. Similar to GPS, OSMTracker is able to record waypoint and also track. If you want to learn more about GPS for field survey, you can see the GPS Module.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>