<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Field Mapping Management on HOT Toolbox</title>
    <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Field Mapping Management on HOT Toolbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pages/field-mapping-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Teams in the Field using OSMTracker and QGIS</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/managing_teams_in_the_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/managing_teams_in_the_field/</guid>
      <description>Overview Central to effective and successful field data collection is a well thought out field data collection plan. This will ensure that field teams face the least number of challenges while out in the field, thus reducing the number of calls for field support coming to the supervisor.
When planning to deploy a team, it is important for the Supervisor to have a good picture of how many work days they have versus the man power available to do the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OSMTrackers</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/using_osm_tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/using_osm_tracker/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Explain OSMTracker as one of survey tools for recording tracks and photos
 How to set up the OSMTracker for the first time
 Learn how to use OSMTracker
  I. What is OSMTracker? OSMTracker is an android application that allows us to record our survey data. Similar to GPS, OSMTracker is able to record waypoint and also track. If you want to learn more about GPS for field survey, you can see the GPS Module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.1 Using ODK Collect</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.1_using_odk_collect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.1_using_odk_collect/</guid>
      <description>Overview Open Data Kit Collect (ODK Collect) is a data collection application on Android. ODK Collect can replace form survey from paper to digital. Therefore, this application will help the mapping and data collection activities in the field which also allow to save the location and photo information at once.
This guide provides surveyors, mappers and field supervisors with the skills to:
 Complete the initial setup for ODK Collect Use ODK Collect for data collection surveys  Initial Setup for ODK Collect 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.2 Using the OpenMapKit Application</title>
      <link>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.2_using_openmapkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/field-mapping-management/5.2_using_openmapkit/</guid>
      <description>Overview OpenMapKit (OMK) is an additional application that is used to support ODK Collect in determining the position of objects found during precise and precise field surveys. OpenMapKit can be run through ODK Collect, after you open and select one of the available forms. In determining the location of an object, OpenMapKit requires a map background in the form of a satellite imagery or OSM map. If you use the OSM as the map background, the thing to note is that the data must be available on the OSM server.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>